Guide to the Abiathar Watkins papers, 1836-1894
The New York Public Library. Manuscripts and Archives Division.
Abiathar Watkins papers
1836-1894
3236
MssCol 3236
Watkins, Abiathar, 1818-
The New York Public Library. Manuscripts and Archives Division. Stephen A. Schwarzman Building Fifth Avenue at 42nd Street, New York, NY 10018-2788
1.3 linear feet (5 boxes)
Abiathar Watkins (1818- ) owned and managed a stagecoach line in upper New York State. Collection consists of papers of Abiathar Watkins and his wife Emily L. Watkins. Includes family correspondence and letters from friends, Emily Watkins's journals and domestic accounts, and stagecoach way-bills. Emily Watkins's journals document her treatment under the care of James C. Jackson at sanatoriums in western New York.
Jackson, James Caleb, 1811-1895; Watkins, Abiathar, 1818-; Watkins, Emily Lewis, 1824-; Watkins family; Coaching (Transportation) -- New York (State); Sanatoriums -- New York (State); Therapeutics -- New York (State); Diaries; New York (State) -- Social life and customs
- Correspondence, 1836-1894
  - 1836-1839 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1840-1844 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1845-1847 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1848-1849 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1850-1852 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1853-1855 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1856-1859 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1860-1861 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1862-1863 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1864-1865 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1866-1868 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1869-1894 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, undated
  - From friends (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - From Sister Kate (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - General (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - General (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
- Journals and receipts, 1840-1870, undated (Box 5)
- Domestic account books, 1847-1852 (Box 5)
- Diaries of Emily Watkins, 1840-1864 (Box 5)
- Inventory of furniture given by Esther Lewis to daughters, 1843-1852 (Box 5)
- Account book of Abiathar Watkins (business and domestic), 1855; 1870 (Box 5)
- Clippings and printed items, 1863-1865, undated (Box 5)
- Receipted bills, domestic remedies, printed items, and miscellaneous, 1845-1889 undated (Box 5)
- Business papers of Abiathar Watkins (Way-bills, etc), 1840-1868 (Box 5)